MARCIO DE FREITAS NASCIMENTO

marciotetzner@gmail.com

CAREER SUMMARY

I have 19 years of Software Developer experience, with the last 13+ years as a Full Stack Developer. I have been a part of many projects. One memorable project I worked on was a freight service system coded in Java. I also consulted on and mentored others working on intranet projects based on a Python Content Management System – CMS – platform.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Brazilian Post Office, Belo Horizonte, MG, Brazil

January 2004 – November 2017

- Web development: constructing and keeping systems that assist Human Resources (legal accident reports), Logistics (managing freight machines) and the Financial Management departments;
- Performance tuning of technologies involving solutions such as Reverse Proxy, HTTP protocol, Load Balancer and Servers of Application, Cache and Web in physical and virtualized hardware. Applied those technics and changed a poor performance intranet to an operable solution with 13k+ workstations of audience.
- Development and consulting for corporate intranet and internet websites;
- Training and mentoring of employees in programming languages;
- Support in installation/settings of Linux Server.

Pharmic – Compounding Pharmacy, Vitoria, ES, Brazil

April 2000 – December 2003

- Software development for production of medicaments (labeling, calculation of formulas, production reports). Developed the upgrade functions into the company systems that allowed them sell and produce homeopathic medicine.
- Workstation park management with six stores and one laboratory: keeping software's platform
 up to date (operation systems, apps in general and licenses), hardware and network maintenance
 along with service providers, and some Windows network configuration.

NetTree– Information Technology and Training, Vitoria, ES, Brazil August 1998 – December 1999

• Software development for financial management of a car retailer; training monitor for programming language courses.

SKILLS AND QUALIFICATIONS

- Languages and Frameworks:
 - ✓ Python (9 years). Development of intranets upon Content Management System CMS Plone;
 - ✓ Java (3 years), Hibernate (2+ years). Development of project for logistics for freight service;
 - ✓ Microsoft SQL Server (7 years), Oracle (6 years);
 - ✓ jQuery (9 years), JavaScript (10+ years), CSS (9+ years), HTML(10+ years), NodeJS (-1 year), Angular (-1 year), Linux Shell(5 years).
 - ✓ C# (-1year), ASP.Net Core (-1 year), Bootstrap (-1 year), Net Core Entity Framework (-1 year), REST APIs (-1year), Web API (-1 year), SOAP web services(+1year)
 - ✓ Flutter (-1 year), Php (-1 year),
 - ✓ ColdFusion (4years) Developing of a variety of business management applications;
- Platforms: Windows (19years), Linux(9years), OSX (3years), VMware (7years);
- Clouding: Azure (-1year);
- Development process: Traditional (based on Rational Unified Process 13years), Agile based on Scrum (2+ years).

EDUCATION

Diploma: Web & Mobile Application Development –New Brunswick Community College – NBCC, Moncton, New Brunswick, Canada (2019 to 2021)

Bachelors' Degree: Computer Science, FAESA – Integrated College of Espirito Santo, Espirito Santo, Brazil (1996 to 2003)